Rohit Varshney rohitvarshney@mail.fresnostate.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/rohit-varshney-16990b74

+1 559-371-5890

SUMMARY: Certified Developer/Software Engineer with an experience in full-stack development with a focus on AWS in application Designing, Analysis, Development, Maintenance and Implementing Enterprise, Web and Client Server Applications and in Cloud Computing Infrastructure such as Amazon Web Services W/ Hands-on Experience on DevOps tools.

EDUCATION:

Master of Science, Computer Science

May 2018

California State University, Fresno (GPA: 3.36/4)

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

May 2014

Uttar Pradesh Technical University, India (GPA: 3.8/4)

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Programmer Analyst, Cognizant Technology Solutions

August 2014- August 2016

- Experience in configure and managing Amazon AWS Cloud Services, EC2, S3, EBS, ELB, Elastic IP, SNS, SQS, Glacier, IAM,
 VPC, Cloud Formation, Route53, Cloud Watch, AWS Code Commit, AWS Code Deploy
- Expertise in working with server side technologies like Node JS, Restful API
- Hands on experience on configuring and using Command Line Interface (CLI) tool to manage AWS Services
- Experience in using Core Technologies HTML, Java Script, JSON, Angular JS, Bootstrap framework, JQuery

Public Relation and Graphic Design Intern, California State University, Fresno CA, USA

March 2017 - Dec 2017

• Responsible for telling the story of Student Involvement programs, including Club Sports and Greek Life through clear, and concise graphics and social media posts

Summer Intern, Hindustan Aeronautics Ltd, India

May 2013 - July 2013

- Software component development in C# and JavaScript
- Website functionality and content management

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Technologies Advance:

- AWS Cloud Services, EC2, S3, API Gateway
- AWS Dynamo DB, Lambda, EBS, ELB, Elastic IP
- AWS SNS, SQS, Route53, RDS
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JSON
- NodeJS, Restful API
- Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes

Technologies Known:

- AngularJS
- Ionic 2, Apache Cordova
- Python, C#, C
- Bootstrap, XML
- Visual Studio, Microsoft Office

PROJECTS:

Encore Tickets | Cognizant Technology Solutions

Dec 2015-Aug 2016

- · Part of a team that was responsible to plan, develop & create mobile applications to match the needs of industrial clients
- I was involved from designing to development phase. Assisted for website and cross platform app
- Gathered business requirements, prepared process flow diagrams, build several prototypes

Retail Assist | Cognizant Technology Solutions

Jan 2015- Dec 2015

- Worked on C# and front end technologies (HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Angular)
- · Assisted in developing several modules for asos.com, an online British fashion and beauty store

CERTIFICATIONS:

- AWS Certified Developer Associate Level (License JWMK1PBCB2R41SWX)
- Microsoft Certified Specialist in HTML5 with CSS3 AND Java Script (Certification number: E208-2988)
- Microsoft Certified Solution Developer of Windows Store Apps Using HTML5 & JavaScript (Cert. no: E240-5133)